

DANIL VOLOSYUK

Senior Frontend Engineer

My experience at the web development is 4 years. I have large experience in web application development, including creating the architecture of the client and server sides, configuring builds, pipelines and deploying apps to cloud services.

Besides that, I think soft skills are just as important as hard skills. Therefore, I am open to feedback and always try to be a good team member. Also can call myself a fast-growing, responsible and multi-tasking person.

(i) CONTACT

- daniil.volosyuk@gmail.com
- danyavol.dev
- t.me/d4nvol
- linkedin.com/in/danyavol
- github.com/danyavol

SKILLS

JavaScript TypeScript Angular

React Vue

HTML CSS SASS/SCSS Less

Angular Material Bootstrap Bulma

Semantic Ul Taiga Ul ApexCharts

Google Charts Husky pre-commit

Git TFS Docker Webpack

Vite RxJS NgRx Redux

Jasmine Jest Karma Vitest

Ionic Capacitor Web/Service Workers

Azure DevOps TeamCity Heroku

GitHub Actions Firebase Netlify

Google Play Console BitBucket

GitLab Jira Railway Figma

Hotjar Newrelic i18n

Google Analytics

Node.js Express MongoDB

PostgreSQL JWT mongoose

cheerio

WORK EXPERIENCE

Feb 2021 current



Frontend Engineer

COHERENT SOLUTIONS - MINSK, WARSAW

Call Center project

The call center with huge configuration, possibility for inbound and outbound calls, and many other features useful for agents.

- Migrated the legacy JS code to Vue.js 3
- Worked closely with the client's team, 95% of communication was in English
- Worked with Azure pipelines

Technologies: Vue.js 2 and 3.4, Vuex, Pinia, TypeScript, Vite, Vitest, ESLint, SCSS, Sip.js, WebSockets(SignalR), Azure DevOps.

Datacenters project

The project is about cloud services, security, datacenters, giving servers in rent, physical access to datacenters. Also it has 3 sub-projects and I worked there, too.

- Migrated pages from Angular.js to Angular 9
- Updated Angular version from 9 to 14
- Analyzed and improved app performance, bundled size reduction
- Created designs of new components and new features, suggested UI and UX improvements
- Set up Angular library with shared components across client sub-projects
- Worked with CI in TeamCity, configured build pipelines in Azure DevOps, restrictions for PRs, branches security
- Meetings with the client. Knowledge transfer meetings for Coherent team and for client team

Have used such technologies as: Typescript, Angular.js, Angular 9-14, Git, TFS, Azure DevOps, TeamCity, RxJs, ApexCharts, Google Charts, Google Maps, Angular Material, ESLint, Jasmine, Karma, Quill.

Oct 2020 -Feb 2021

Frontend Developer

PRIVATE CLIENT FROM CANADA

Developed a front-end part of the control panel of the company to be used by employees (add/edit products, contacts, events; statistics, dashboards, etc.) and helped a little bit with back-end part.

Technologies: jQuery, HTML, CSS, JS, Front (Bootstrap 4 based template), Java, Spring.

Feb 2023 - current

Software Engineer

MONEY SPLITTER - PERSONAL PROJECT

This app is intended to help people split their bills in the trips, when organizing events or when just paying in restaurants. Existing similar apps have different disadvantages so currently I am working on building a better app and planning to earn money on it.

Technologies: Angular 15+, Angular Material, Ionic, Capacitor, OAuth, Firebase, Google Cloud, Android

Apr 2020 -Jul 2022

Software Engineer

STUDY BUDDY - PERSONAL PROJECT

This app is supposed to make the life of students easier and comfortable. More than 1800 students from my university were using the Telegram bot and web app. Developed the functionality of group schedule, teachers schedule, personal balance in university, notifications about changes, daily reminders about lessons, schedule archive, etc.

Technologies: JavaScript, Node.js, telegraf, HTML parsing, Angular 12, Angular Material, ApexCharts, Node.js, TypeScript, Express, JWT, MongoDB, Netlify, Heroku

EDUCATION

Apr 2024

JavaScript conference (3 days)

HOLY JS

Dec 2023 (

Security Testing Training

COHERENT SOLUTIONS - INTERNAL TRAINING

Nov 2023

Angular and JavaScript conference (3 days)

NG POLAND

Jun 2023

Node.js Training

COHERENT SOLUTIONS - INTERNAL TRAINING

Mar 2023

React Training

COHERENT SOLUTIONS - INTERNAL TRAINING

Apr 2021

Angular Training

COHERENT SOLUTIONS - INTERNAL TRAINING

Feb 2019 -Dec 2019 Frontend Developer Courses

IT ACADEMY STEP - MINSK

During the course I have learned all basic technologies needed to apply for Junior Frontend position and a little bit more. Also learned basics of Angular and React frameworks.

2018 - 2022

Bachelor's Degree

INTERNATIONAL UNIVERSITY MITSO

Specialization - Information systems and technologies



- English (B2 Level)
- Russian (Native)
- Belarusian (Native)
- Polish (A1 Level)